icbc.com 2019-06-04

# Website privacy statement

Your privacy is important to us. This privacy statement describes the information we collect via the ICBC website (www.icbc.com), how we collect and use that information and how we protect your privacy.

### What personal information we collect

  * We do not collect personal information unless our website visitors volunteer it.

  * When you respond to games on our site, we may collect personal information such as your name and email address.

  * When you complete online transactions, job applications, or enter our online surveys or contests, we may collect personal information such as your name, address, email address and your internet IP address.

  * When you voluntarily send us electronic mail, we collect your email address, your internet IP address and your message so that we may reply to you.

  * We use cookies on this website to allow you to properly navigate the site, to collect aggregated statistics and to remember your settings. We do not use cookies to collect any personal information except where it is explicitly expressed.   

### What session information we collect

  * We keep no individual visitor data.

  * When you visit the ICBC website, our web server automatically collects a small amount of information (for example, browser type and referring webpage) to help us manage and improve our website. This information is aggregated, and is never used for individual tracking. It is only used to report our visitors' collective viewing habits and technical environment. 

###  Email caution

Please note, email is not a secure method of transmitting sensitive personal information and by using this website and/or online services you accept this risk. Email you send to us is not encrypted. Your email may be intercepted by other Internet users, without your knowledge or permission, while in transit to us. We don't recommend emailing information that you consider confidential to us.

### How we protect and use the personal information that we collect

  * ICBC's collection, use, disclosure and retention of information complies with the provisions of the Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act. Collected information is used only by authorized ICBC staff to fulfil the purpose for which it was originally collected, or other purposes which will be described in the transaction you are completing.

  * We will not sell or trade any personally identifiable information that may be collected from our Web site and will not disclose such information to third parties except as authorized by law.

  * When you send us electronic mail via our website, your message is stored as business correspondence accessible only to authorized ICBC website staff.

### Links to other sites

Our website contains links to other websites. Please be aware that privacy policies vary from site to site. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of other websites to which our site may link.

## Social media collection policy (Twitter)

  * The personal information you post may be collected by the Insurance Corporation of British Columbia (ICBC) under s. 26(c) of the Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act for the purposes of engaging and consulting with the public. Please be aware that any information collected may be stored and/or accessed outside of Canada on servers not belonging to ICBC.

  * To protect your own privacy and the privacy of others, please do not include any personal information including phone numbers and email addresses in the body of your comment. Please do not share personal information about others, including pictures.

## Social media collection policy (Facebook)

  * Facebook requires us (pursuant to section 5.7 of their Statement of Rights and Responsibilities) to notify you that by posting comments on this site you are consenting to the collection of the information you provide.

  * The Insurance Corporation of British Columbia (ICBC) will collect information that relates directly to and is necessary for an operating program or activity of ICBC. Personal information that is collected is done so under the authority of s. 26(c) of the Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act for the purposes of engaging and consulting with the public. Please be aware that any information collected may be stored and/or accessed outside of Canada on servers not belonging to ICBC.

  * To protect your own privacy and the privacy of others, please do not include any personal information including phone numbers and email addresses in the body of your comment. Please do not share personal information about others, including pictures.  

## Qmatic SMS texting service

  * ICBC sometimes allows visitors to our driver licensing offices to sign up for an SMS text message that will let them know when they are close to the front of the queue.

  * If you have signed up for this service, you will receive up to three text messages from us. The first message confirms your sign-up to the service and provides a link to contact us. The second message tells you to return to the office soon. The third message closes the ticket, and may include a link to a survey for you to provide your feedback.

  * If you have not signed up for this service and are receiving SMS text messages from us in error, or if you have decided you do not wish to be notified via SMS to return to the office, you can end the service by replying with STOP.  

### Changes to this privacy statement

ICBC may revise this privacy statement from time to time to reflect changes to our website, social media and online services. 

Last updated: July 31, 2018
